# **Amber Whizin**

831-607-9902 | Cambridge, MA | amberwhizin@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/amberwhizin/ | github.com/amberwhizin https://www.amberwhizin.com

# **Front-End Engineer**

An ever learning front-end software engineer with 10+ years in customer support. Motivated and committed to problem-solving with a passion for JavaScript. A highly skilled collaborator with a focus on creating customer-driven improvements and writing effective code. Bottom line, a determined user advocate in building scalable and interactive websites.

### **Skills**

Fullstack Applications | Debugging | Customer Service Management | Team Training | RESTful API's | Object-Oriented Programming | Relational Databases & Non-Relational Databases | Collaborate with Front-End/Back-End Developers User Advocate | Heroku | Flex-Box

# **Technologies**

**Languages**: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, Node.js, EJS **Front-End Libraries and Frameworks**: React, JQuery, Phaser

Databases: MongoDB, SQL

**Back-End Frameworks**: Mongoose, Express **Developer Toolkit**: Github, Git, PostgreSQL

# **Projects**

#### **Connect Four Game**

- Game: amberwhizin.github.io/connect 4/
- Assembled a game after Connect 4 with JQuery, HTML5, and CSS3.
- Developed a Front-End game where users can drag/drop or click columns/rows to place coins.
- Trouble-shot and completed the game logic to win horizontally, vertically, and diagonally.

### TellyCritic - A Review Site

- Site: https://telly-critic.herokuapp.com/sessions/new
- Designed a review site so users can record their private thoughts on films and television series.
- Generated with Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, styled with CSS3 and Bootstrap, and coded with EJS, HTML5.
- Tackled express-session/bcrypt and security error messages to turn out a private login page.

### What-A-Bore -Entertainment App

- Site: <a href="https://whatabore.herokuapp.com/">https://whatabore.herokuapp.com/</a>
- Designed an entertainment application that diverts user's attention from apathy to gaiety.
- Coordinated a group project in launching a modern React application using Spotify's Third-party API.
- Spearheaded a Full-Stack application using Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, and refined with React Bootstrap.

# <u>CarefulFriends - A Wellness App</u>

- Site: https://carefulfriends-client.herokuapp.com/
- Produced a wellness app for people in turmoil to create healthy exercise habits.
- Implemented a Full-Stack application using MERN with full CRUD, polished with Bootstrap.
- Explored JSON Web Tokens and discovered intriguing challenges setting cookies with React.

# **Education**

### General Assembly, Boston, MA

Certificate 2020

- Achieved a certificate of completion in an immersive software engineering program with over 480+ hours
  of intensive fast-paced learning.
- Built creative and unique sites that challenged students to become fluent in the most current programming languages.

# **Professional Experience**

# Freelance Software Engineer, Somerville, MA

2019 - Present

#### Freelance

- Self-studied and pair-programmed with the Codecademy community.
- Iterated and persisted in solving complex problems with JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3.

# Whole Foods Market, Somerville, MA

2017 - 2019

### Clerk

- Maximized group performance and maintained high satisfaction with customers.
- Communicated and assisted 70+ customers a day.
- Mentored new employees on how to effectively perform on the job.

### OSI International School of Sarajevo, Bosnia

2017

### Volunteer - Teaching Assistant

Assisted with, motivated, and encouraged 100+ students in Reading, Math, and English.

# Delaware North Companies, Yosemite National Park, CA

2015 - 2016

Front-Desk - Yosemite Valley Lodge

- Effectively unified the members of my team by addressing concerns and problem-solving.
- Determinedly studied customer needs and enabled the hotel's success.

# The Food Bin Inc., Santa Cruz, CA

2009 - 2014

### Manager

- Managed 15+ employees for 4+ years.
- Coordinated schedules, mentored employees, and responded to customer feedback.